

vigneshkannaiyan.official@gmail.com, 9952209682

#### Summary:

Multitalented Software Developer with experience in software industry. Demonstrated excellent skills in NodeJs, ExpressJs, NestJs, ReactJs, Prisma ORM, MongoDB, My SQL, Sequelize Js, JavaScript, ReactJs, Microservices, Jenkins, docker, kubernetes, podman and SIEM tools. True team player with strengths in adaptability and accuracy.

Also fast learner and able to adapt myself in a new technology or a new programming language. *Interested in contributing myexpertise in front end development and deployments*.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Software Developer

IBM India Pvt. Ltd - Kochi, Kerala November 2023 to April 2024

Project Title: Cloud Pak For Data (CP4D)

## **Description:**

IBM Cloud Pak® for Data is a modular set of integrated software components for data analysis, organization and management. It is available for self-hosting, or as a managed service on IBM Cloud & others. Break down data silos, Access data across business silos, on premises and in clouds, without moving the data. Keep data private and secure, Universally safeguard data usage with privacy and usage policy enforcement across all data. Empower all data consumers, Enable users of all skill levels to access trusted data with tailored interfaces (Code, Canvas, No Code).

#### Role:

- Backend codes are developed using Golang and the front end is on React Js (This is specified to the module which we handled).
- Writing the React Js code for the given designs and changes.
- Deploying the build in the docker using jenkins.
- Integrated with various SIEM tools such as Splunk, Mezmo, Papertrails for tracking and monitoring the all kind of security events.
- Also forwarded the logs to Kafka to check, tracking and monitoring the all kind of security events with and without TLS.

# **Software Developer**

Mobile Programming Inc Pvt. Ltd - Chennai, TamilNadu May 2022 to November 2023

Project Title: Adani One (Adani Digital Labs)

#### **Description:**

Adanione is product where a user can book air tickets, train tickets, hotel stay, travel packages, cabs, porter service, duty free items and also a meet and greet service name Pranaam all mode of payments are integrated withJusPay. The user will be rewarded by reward points and various coupon codes. The main scope of the product is to give the user un paralleled experience of travel and lifestyle across the nation.

#### Role:

- Backend codes are developed using NodeJs with the framework NestJs.
- Developed database integration in MongoDB using Prisma ORM and used BullMQ for jobs and schedulers.
- Writing the complex calculation algorithms for the payments, coupons and reward points.
- Writing the swagger file using nestjs/swagger in the controller files.

- Integrated with various third party api's for the microservices for all the available services in the application.
- Data base used are MongoDB, Prisma ORM and payment gateway is JusPay.

Project Title: Market 360 (eClerx)

#### Description:

Market 360 is the application where we can track the movement of sales, stock, inventory movement of the products. The users and providers have the separate portals in the application. The outlets can track their sales and stock and inventory movements of each products. Likewise the product manufacturers also track their sales, stock

and inventory movements. Yearly, Monthly, Weekly and daily movements can be tracked by various graphs and filters like graphs, pie charts and so on.

#### Role:

- Backend codes are developed using NodeJs using th ExpressJs frame work.
- Developed database integration in MongoDB.
- Writing the complex calculation aggregation queries respective to the requirements.

## Software Developer

OASYS Cybernetics Pvt. Ltd - Chennai, TamilNadu March 2021 to May 2022

Project Title: HMIS (Health Management Information System)

### Description:

A web application for monitoring the Hospital details such as patients information, doctor's information, hospital staffs information, assets information, inventory information etc. Based on the roles given to user their access in theapplication also varies. Main scope of this application is reduce the time consumption occurs in this department. Not only doctors and patients information the dealers and manufacturers, drivers, launderers and who are all associated with the hospital environment are also gets benefits by this application. This project is currently in live for **Government of Maharashtra**.

#### Role:

- Writing backend codes using NodeJs which performs the CRUD operations, bulk data upload and download.
- Developed database integration in MySql using Sequelize. Js and also in MongoDB.
- Writing the complex queries for the database to get the data in respective of search (In both MySql and MongoDB).
- Creating unit test cases for all the api's in the backend using the node module mocha, chai.
- Writing the swagger documentation file using the node module swagger.
- Setting up the swagger documentation file for ws02.
- Data base used are MongoDB and MySql (Sequelize is)

# Software Developer

Comorin Consulting Services- Bengaluru, Karnataka Aug 2020 to October 2020

Project Title: CPOS

#### Description:

A web application for recruiting the new candidates. Based on the various level of hierarchies in the organization the recruitment process of the candidate flows through the application. Initially a candidate will come in as New Candidate andhis flow end as Selected Candidate or Rejected candidates based on the decision of the designated person in the hierarchy. Andthe candidate who are all put on hold are also referred in the future. The main focus of this application is to make the recruitment process simple and easier.

#### Role:

- Creating unit test cases for all the api's in the backend using the node module mocha ,chai .
- Writing the swagger documentation file using the node module swagger.
- Setting up the test server using ngrok and assisted the integration with the frontend (Angular Js).
- Writing backend codes using NodeJs which performs the user profile validation, report generation, bulk data upload and download.
- Developed database integration using MongoDB.

## **Project Title:** Cable Pay

#### **Description:**

A web application for monitoring the internet services provided by the organization. There we can track what type of connection providing, type of payment method, location of the client who got the service, admin details, employeedetails, customer details, distributor details, invoice, billing history, collected amount, pre payment amount, pending

amount, plan validity, existing plans, plan renewals, changes of plans everything can be tracked and monitored in this web application.

#### Role:

- Creating unit test cases for all the api's in the backend using the node module mocha ,chai .
- Writing the swagger documentation file using the node module swagger.
- Setting up the test server using ngrok and assisted the integration with the frontend (Angular Js).
- Writing backend codes using NodeJs which performs the user profile validation, report generation, bulk data upload anddownload.
- Developed database integration using MongoDB.

Agilite Group Technologies Pvt Ltd - Hyderabad, Telangana July 2018 to June 2020

## Project Title: Tool and Die Management

#### **Description:**

A web application for the storage and analysis of 'tools', 'machines' which are all engaged in producing the 'components' which are the end products of Industry. There are various hierarchies available from organization head to store-keeper and each user are restricted with certain priorities in application. The ultimate part of the application is the Blockchain' which differs it from other applications.

#### Role:

- Writing backend codes using NodeJs which performs the user profile validation, report generation, bulk data upload anddownload.
- Developed database integration using MongoDB.
- Created Blockchain network using Hyperledger Composer and Hyperledger Fabric which provides the security and trust overthe peer networks.
- Report generation are done using TIBCO Jaspersoft. In this we can download the individual or bulk data in pdf or excel formatas per the user's wish.

# **Project Title:** Bunkering Solutions

# **Description:**

Bunkering is supplying a ship with fuel, lubricating oils, potable water which is usually happens in a port. The navy and number of companies already bunker at sea it saves lot of time and money. But bunkering in ports also causes port congestion, because other vessels have to wait for a berthing place when a vessel is bunkering. Bunkering in sea can be complicated in bad weather conditions, so we developed a system in which we can monitor the process of bunkering. And also this can reduce the risk of port congestion. Using this we can track and monitor the availability of the ports.

#### Role:

- Writing backend codes using NodeJs which performs the user profile validation, report generation, bulk data upload anddownload.
- Developed database integration using MongoDB.
- Created separate user profile for the flexibility fo the users, email validation and passwaord validation are done using nodemailer and encrypt, bcrypt respectively.
- Report generation are done using TIBCO Jaspersoft. In this we can download the individual or bulk data in pdf or excel formatas per the user's wish.

## Technologies Used:

- NodeJs
- NestJs
- ReactJs
- Prisma
- JusPay
- Javascript
- MongoDB
- MySQL
- Sequelize Js
- Express Js
- Jenkins
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- SIEM Tools
- Kafka
- JSON
- Rest API
- Blockchain
- TIBCO Jaspersoft
- Ubuntu (OS)

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology Anna University 2014 to 2018

Higher Secondary(12th Pass) M.Najappa Chettiar Matric Hr.Sec School August 2012 to March 2014

# **SKILLS / IT SKILLS**

- Node js
- MongoDB
- My Sql
- Sequelizer
- JavaScript
- React.js
- Kafka
- SIEM Tools
- TIBCO Jaspersoft
- Postman API
- Talend Open Studio

# **ONLINE PROFILE**

http://linkedin.com/in/vignesh-kannaiyan-b40ab718b